JOSE ALFONSO GARCIA

(830)513-4074

joseagarcia98.jg@gmail.com

San Marcos, TX

Education

Texas State University B.S Computer Science Summer 2020 Major GPA 3.23

Experience With

C++ • Java • C • Python • GitHub • Sklearn • MPI • Data Structures • Object Orientation

Courses

Data Structures Object Orientation Assembly Language Software Engineering **Advance Algorithms** Computer Architecture Intro to Machine Learning **Parallel Programming**

Links



https://github.com/ JoseGarcia-Txst



https:// www.hackerrank.com/ JoseGarcia Txst

Relevant Experience

ICPC Texas State Texas - Mexico Spring 2019 Placed 4th out of 25 Teams. Completed 3 problems in the completion with my Team (C++)

Regional ICPC (International Collegiate Programming Contest) Fall 2018 Placed 39th out of 74 Teams. Completed 3 problems in the competition with my Team (C++).

Competitive Coding

Fall 2018 - Spring 2019 Practiced competitive coding problems once a week with team. Had daily trainings/

Work Experience

iOS Advisor

July 2018 - Present

Apple, San Marcos, TX

meetings 2 weeks before competition.

Adapted to new products quickly to assist with issues. I Altered conversation to customer's needs/preferences. What I makes me excel as an Advisor is that I take the customers problems as if it was my own, also I keep a positive mindset though every call which the caller can hear though my attitude.

Supplemental Instructor Leader (Foundations of CS II) Aug 2017 - June 2018 Texas State University, San Marcos, TX

Facilitated sessions for students three times a week. Constructed lesson plans for sessions. Planned and used a variety of teaching and learning methods. Demonstrated effective study strategies for students. Developed time management skills.

About Me

Im 20 years old and I love problem solving. Currently I love being an iOS Advisor because it's allows me to use my problem solving abilities. My first time getting into coding was when I was 13 and developed my own server for Minecraft. It was all in Java, I was able to work around it with online forms and tutorials and many hours put in. Now I'm glad that I found something I love doing. My main interest with Computer Science is Artificial Intelligence I personally think that it's going to be amazing to see what computers are going to be capable of in the future.